In the year 845...
the Colossal and Armored
Titans suddenly appeared,
destroying the wall,
along with the life we'd known.
Humanity abandoned Wall Maria,
losing twenty percent of its population
and a third of its territory,
to retreat within Wall Rose.
And in the year 850...
The Colossal Titan reappeared
and breached the wall.
And once again, humanity could
not stop a Titan invasion.
Soldiers fell, one after the
next, before the Titan assault.
And then...
Eren! Hurry!
Eren Jaeger had been
devoured by a Titan,
but reappeared, emerging
from a mysterious Titan.
Attention!
Dot Pixis, the high commander
of the southern territories,
recognized the combat potential
of Eren's ability to become a Titan,
and decided to execute
an audacious plan.
He will become a Titan,
pick up the giant boulder
by the shattered gate, carry it over,
and seal the hole.
When this mission succeeds,
humanity will have retaken
its territory from them
for the very first time.
But for humanity, that step will be
a great advance in our
attack on the Titans!
However, as soon as it has begun, the mission
already seems to be on the brink of failure...
Wound
The Battle for Trost (8)
We've somehow managed
to lure most of the Titans
to the town's edge...
But despite our best
efforts to avoid combat,
we've lost around twenty
percent of our troops.
We didn't lose them.
Those soldiers didn't die on their own.
They died due to my orders.
This battle will decide
humanity's survival.
And to win, I am willing
to be called a murderer.
Ackerman!
Hey! Ackerman, stop!
Get away from him!
Eren, don't you know who I am?
It's me, Mikasa!
Your family!
You must use that boulder
to seal the hole!
The mission has failed.
I knew there wasn't any secret weapon.
Eren, you're human!
You're...
Move, Ackerman!
What the?
He's just like any other stupid Titan!
Eren!
Captain Ian!
Two Titans approaching from the front!
A 10-meter and a 6-meter class.
Another from the rear, as well!
One 12-meter class coming this way!
Ian, we must retreat!
Look at him!
No way is that hole getting sealed!
Yeah...
We have no choice but to leave him here.
Red smoke round from the
elite force sighted.
A serious problem has happened
during the mission.
We're dying for no reason.
My friends died for nothing!
Hey! Look at that!
What? What is that?
It... failed?
Why?
Hey, Armin!
Where are you going?
Commander Pixis,
we should recall them
to defend the gate.
Shall I do it?
No.
Shouldn't we order the
elite force to retreat?
No.
Continue drawing the Titans
to the edge of town.
The elite force has full
tactical discretion.
They are not simply excellent soldiers.
They're the best of the best,
entrusted with humanity's fate.
For them to give up so easily
would be unimaginable.
They'll fight to the end...
So the deaths of the fallen will
not have been in vain.
Hey, what's wrong?
Give the order!
Ian, it wasn't your fault!
The plan was always a long shot.
Everyone knew that.
It was worth trying, and we
took our best shot!
Come on! Our squads will climb the walls.
Wait!
Wait...
Calm down, Ackerman.
Riko, your squad will handle the
12-meter Titan behind us.
Mitabi's squad and mine will
take the two in front.
What?
I'm the one they left in charge!
Shut up and follow your orders!
We can't leave Jaeger defenseless.
I'm changing the plan.
We protect Jaeger from the Titans
until we can retrieve him.
He's still valuable as one
of humanity's last hopes.
We cannot just abandon him like this.
We can be replaced, but he can't be.
The failure of that
dysfunctional human weapon
has already cost several hundred lives!
You're saying we should bring him
back, so this can happen again?
That's right.
We must try as many times as necessary,
regardless of the cost in lives!
What happened to Eren?
Armin's headed there by himself.
He's probably all right.
Probably?
He's fine.
I'm sure of it.
Eren can do this.
I think luring the Titans to the
town's edge is useless.
Any fight with Titans
is a war of attrition.
At this stage, they want to avoid
the needless loss of troops.
Then anyone who doesn't make it now
will have died for nothing?
Eventually, it will become an all-out war.
But until then, we must
preserve our forces.
It's obvious that we should
minimize casualties.
The brass made the right call.
Is that so, huh?
It is!
Anyway...
Let's both ensure that we
don't end up as casualties.
Ian, are you serious?
How else should humanity
defeat the Titans?
Riko, tell me!
Is there any other way to get
ourselves out of this mess?
Some way to maintain our human dignity,
without more deaths?!
How can we counter the Titans'
overwhelming advantage over us?
As if I'd know of a way to defeat them!
That's right...
So for the moment, this is
all we can and should do.
We must be willing to sacrifice our lives
and do our best for that
incomprehensible human weapon.
Pathetic, isn't it?
But as humans, it's all we can do.
Now, what will you do?
This is the only battle we can fight.
This is the struggle we've
been allowed to engage.
I can't accept that.
Riko!
I'll obey the order.
I think what you're saying is right.
But as we struggle our hardest,
we'll also show them
how terrifying humans can be.
I refuse to die for nothing.
Leave the 12-meter class
behind us to my squad.
Let's go.
Our target will be the two in the front.
Yeah.
Thank you, Captain Ian.
Ackerman, there's no need to thank me.
I was terrified because there's
no telling what you'll do.
Do as you like, just as
in the original plan.
That will be a more efficient
use of your abilities.
Yes, sir.
You have to protect your boyfriend.
We're family.
What?
The damaged parts aren't regenerating?
Is it due to the earlier damage he took?
What will that do to Eren?
And is there any guarantee
he can regain human form?
No, stop this.
I will not be able to find
answers to these questions.
For now, I'll just do what I can.
Eren...
Mikasa! What happened?
Information We Can Share So Far:
3D Maneuver Gear Weight-Shifting Device (3)
Users must shift their entire weight to
one side of their hips or the other.
This permits acrobatic movement,
but heavily taxes the muscles.
Information We Can Share So Far:
3D Maneuver Gear Training (3)
For this reason, instructors will deliberately
cut student lifelines to gauge reactions.
While unsafe, anyone who dies during
training would be unable to fight Titans anyway.
What?
What... am I doing now?
Am I sitting?
I can't see a thing.
What day is it?
Where am I?
Hmm?
I'm at home?
I'll go back to sleep.
Eren!
What are you doing, Eren?
Listen up.
You just need to keep the Titans
in the corner of the city.
Stay focused on that,
and draw them there.
Got it?
You don't need to fight.
Trainees, form groups of three
and run along the ground.
When you reach the wall, jump up.
Don't get killed.
If any Titans break away,
we'll take care of them.
"If"?
Isn't it more of a "when" than an "if"?
If we think we're in danger,
can we deviate from our orders?
If you believe it'll help.
Kirschstein squad, go!
Right!
This is bad! Behind us!
One 13-meter class!
It's approaching Jaeger!
More Titans coming through the hole!
Four Titans, approximately
10-meter class!
Ackerman, take the one behind us!
Got it.
Don't let it near Jaeger!
We'll stop them here!
Right!
Even if they are elite, two squads
can't handle four at once...
No...
Why are there so many Titans?
There aren't too many people there.
Could Eren be drawing them?
Mikasa!
What happened to the plan?
Armin!
What happened to Eren?
It's dangerous! Move back!
Eren is completely unable to enact
his will through that Titan!
I spoke to it, but it
didn't recognize me!
There's no point in anyone else trying!
What about the plan?
It failed.
Everyone's fighting because
we can't leave Eren.
But there are too many...
Before long, they'll wipe us out.
The spot on the back of the neck,
ten centimeters across and a meter high.
Armin!
I'll get Eren out of here!
You protect us from any Titans!
What are you saying?
Eren came out of the
Titan's vital point.
It's probably related to the
mystery behind them.
Don't worry.
As long as I avoid striking
it in the center,
he won't die.
It'll just hurt...
a tiny bit!
Armin...
Armin, that's insane! Stop!
Mikasa, do what you can!
If you go, some lives might be saved!
Leave Eren to me!
Eren, can you hear me?
Come to your senses!
If we don't get out of
here, we'll all die!
Don't let the Titan's body take over!
Just come out of that
lump of flesh, now!
Come out?
Why?
I'm tired...
Eren! Get out of there!
Hurry!
Eren! Eren!
What happened to avenging your mother?
Aren't you going to wipe out the Titans?
Don't you hate the things
that killed your mother?
What are you talking about, Armin?
Mom's right here...
Eren! Eren!
Wake up, Eren!
You're still in there, aren't you?
If we stay here, the
Titans will kill us!
Everything will end here!
Like I said...
I don't understand you, Armin.
Why do I have to leave?
Yeah...
Why would I want to leave?
Why would I want to
join the Survey Corps?
Looks like we have to deviate
from the plan, like it or not.
Gotcha!
So you're finally down, bastard?
Fall back for now!
I'm here.
I'll join up with Mitabi's squad.
What?!
Jean!
Hurry! Go!
I won't let anyone else
die because of me!
Damn it... A malfunction,
at a time like this?
Jean!
What's wrong?
Why isn't he using his Maneuver Gear?
No way... Is it broken?
I'll come up with something!
Damn it.
Why am I the one slowing us down?
Can I really come up with something?
Eren...
Eren!
One day, we're going to explore
the outside world, right?
Far beyond these walls
is flaming water! Frozen earth!
Snow-white plains of sand!
The world my mom and dad tried to see...
I thought maybe you'd forgotten.
But the reason you stopped mentioning it
was because you didn't want me
to join the Survey Corps, right?
The outside world?
Eren... Answer me!
You knew that hell was one
step beyond the walls.
You might die horribly,
like my mom and dad did.
So why did you want to go?
Why?
You know why.
Because I was born into this world!
Go. Run. Live.
Those words fill the air,
as many lives are lost
on the battlefield.
Eren heads for the gate,
carrying hope with him.
Primal Desires
The Battle for Trost (9)